

# Patrick A. Jain-Taylor

San Jose, CA • (508) 565-8116 • patrick.andrew.taylor@gmail.com

# Cloud Architect | DevOps Engineer











Professional Cloud Architect and DevOps Engineer with 10+ years of experience in Information Technology in Financial & Mental Health Services. Skilled in Amazon Web Services, Terraform, Kubernetes, Python, and Networking. Strong focus on leadership, team building, and organizational advancement. How can I help?

Contact me

# **Experience**

## Lyra Health

Manager, DevOps • Jul. 2022 - Present

Drives initiatives to standardize our cloud deployments, zero-trust network access, Agile workflows, and DevOps best practices for the broader organization.

- Rebuilt DevOps Agile program from the ground up to support daily standups, weekly backlog grooming, bi-weekly ceremonies, and quarterly initative planning to keep our program deliveries on-time; established as a model now used by multiple TechOps organizations.
- Led initiative to migrate away from our legacy zero-trust network access (ZTNA) solution to Banyan Security (now SonicWall Cloud Secure Edge) ZTNA; now supports 1000 services across 3000 internal users.

- Deployed AWS Control Tower in our AWS Organization to deploy new AWS accounts with necessary security controls & governance, deploy well-architected solutions to our accounts using Account Factory for Terraform, and support future initiatives to fan out our existing applications into dedicated account stacks.
- Mentors mid-level, senior, and staff colleagues through dedicated 1-on-1 time, scheduled office hours, and a bi-weekly show & tell event for all DevOps members to demonstrate their work to the team and critical stakeholders.
- Provides architectural & engineering support for internal security trainings with phishing simulations, including the management of Well-Architected ACM, ELB, IAM, Route 53, ACM, SES, VPC, and WAF services.
- Manages a global cloud network using AWS Network Manager, to reduce our reliance on VPC peering, ensure reachability of resources across regions, analyze & enforce least-privileged access between resources, and manage IP space effectively as we scale.

#### Lyra Health

Lead, DevOps Engineer • Jul. 2022 — Present

## Lyra Health

Senior DevOps Engineer • Jul. 2022 - Present

#### Eaton Vance Management, a Morgan Stanley company

Cloud Architect, Core Services • Jan. 2019 — Jun. 2022

Subject matter expert on all things cloud, leading efforts in architecting, engineering, and operating in AWS.

#### **Eaton Vance Management**

Network Automation Engineer • Oct. 2017 — Jan. 2019

Focused on automating traditional enterprise networking infrastructure with Python scripting and Ansible playbooking.

## **SS&C Technologies**

Network Engineer • Oct. 2013 — Oct. 2017

## **Columbia University**

Various Roles, CU Information Technology (CUIT) • Sept. 2012 — May. 2014

#### **General Dynamics**

Intern • May. 2013 — Aug. 2013

#### **Providence College**

Various Roles, PC Information Technology (PCIT) & Ghana Sustainable Aid Project (GSAP) • Sept. 2010 — Aug. 2012

## **Certification**

#### **Terraform Associate**

Hashicorp • 2020

#### **AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate**

Amazon Web Services • 2019

## **Programming with Python**

Codecademy • 2018

## **CCNA Routing & Switching**

Cisco • 2015

### **Education**

#### **Columbia University**

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering • 2012 — 2014

#### **Providence College**

Bachelor of Arts, Pre-Engineering • 2009 — 2012

# **Technologies**

#### **Amazon Web Services**

Auto Scaling, Backup, Certificate Manager, CloudFormation, CloudFront, CloudWatch Logs, Config, Control Tower, Direct Connect, DynamoDB, EBS, ECR, ECS, EKS, ELB, EventBridge, IAM, Kinesis Data Streams & Firehose, KMS, Lambda, PrivateLink, RDS, Route 53, Route 53 Resolver, S3, Security Groups, Secrets Manager, SNS, SQS, Step Functions, Transit Gateway, VPC, WAF

#### **Third-Party Cloud Services**

Artifactory, Bridgecrew, CloudHealth, Datadog, Nexus, Opal, Prisma, Snowflake, Sonatype, Splunk, Sumo Logic, Wiz

#### Infrastructure as Code & Configuration Management

Terraform, CloudFormation, Ansible, Chef

#### **Containerization & Orchestration**

Docker, Kubernetes

#### **Continuous Integration & Continuous Delivery**

Github Actions, GitLab Runner, Jenkins

#### **Programming Languages**

Python, Bash/ZSH

#### **Agile Technologies**

Atlassian Jira & Confluence

#### **Networking**

Cisco, Juniper, Aruba, Palo Alto Networks, Netskope, Banyan

# **Associations**

# **Hack.Diversity**

Mentor • 2021 - 2024

Hack Diversity is a talent provider of Black & Latinx technologists, supporting underrepresented talent with a yearly fellowship and incubator program. I serve in a mentor role to Hack fellows, and provide education in cloud technologies.

Inspired by  $\underline{@jglovier}$ . Source project can be forked from  $\underline{GitHub}$ .